# Jonathan Chuang

jchuangsa@gmail.com www.jycdesigns.com 206-457-9205 3310 NE 123rd St. Seattle, WA 98125

#### PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

Experience in cross-disciplined teams contributing to both front end development and UX design, utilizing Adobe XD, Figma, HTML, CSS, and Javascript (React).

Passionate about taking a UX centred approach to front end development and being the person on a team to bridge the gap between designers and developers.

1 of 3 students selected for exchange with the Universität Heidelberg in Germany.

#### **PROJECTS**

## **Symposia (Capstone Project)** — Front End Developer & UI/UX Designer

Engineered a React web application to promote media literacy and a more holistic news diet utilizing machine learning (NLP) and data visualizations in D3.

Conducted user research and synthesized results to make improvements

Collaborated closely with a multidisciplinary team to execute a product plan, and create a well rounded application within the set constraints and time provided.

#### **Personal Portfolio Project** — Developer / Designer

Developed a variety of projects, to improve my skills and explore new areas of engineering and UX design.

Created responsive portfolio website in React using the Gatsby Frontend Framework and GraphQL

#### **ChocolateBook** — Front End Developer/UX Designer

Researched, designed, and developed a web application for chocolate enthusiasts to record and review their chocolate eating experiences.

Built in React and D3 in the frontend and utilized Firebase for the backend.

#### **WORK EXPERIENCE**

## Ugly Mug Café University District — Barista/Server

2019 - 2020

Prepared a variety of high quality food and drink in a fast paced service environment.

Collaborated closely with coworkers in an autonomous environment to optimize service during peak hours.

Monitored changing guidelines during the Covid-19 pandemic, and adapted company practices to provide a safe environment for staff and customers.

Maintained accurate inventory count to support operations.

### **UW Transportation Services** — *Student Assistant*

2017 - 2019

Worked with UW staff on logistical planning for University of Washington events Optimized the flow of foot traffic, car traffic, and parking strategy across campus.

Provided customer service and navigation assistance to campus visitor's.

#### **EDUCATION**

#### **University of Washington**

Seattle, Washington • 2019

## (Seattle) Bachelor of Informatics (Human-Computer Interaction)

Dean's Honor Roll 2016-2019

3.81 GPA

UXU club member

#### Universität Heidelberg

Heidelberg, Germany • 2018

Direct Exchange

Semester Exchange at the University of Heidelberg

Badem Württemberg Scholarship for University Exchange

#### **Earl Haig Secondary School**

Toronto, Ontario • 2015

#### **SKILLS**

#### Web development Languages

Javascript (React), HTML, CSS, GraphQL, Gatsby

#### Wireframing/Prototyping

Figma, Adobe XD

#### User research

User testing & interviews

#### **LANGUAGES**

English, Mandarin, German